

### LANGUAGES

#### Italian

Native or Bilingual proficiency.

# **English**

Professional working proficiency.

### **SKILLS**

I work proactively in order to find the conditions of maximum cooperation and dialogue: I like teamwork.

With the clients, I always try to establish a constructive dialogue in order to better understand their needs.

Solid experience with design systems, atomic design, responsive design, UCD and accessibility principles.

# Excellent knowledge

Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD

# Good knowledge

Zeplin, Principle, HTML & CSS

### Basic knowledge

Autocad, Processing, Keyshot and Cinema4D, Rhinoceros

### **TAX CODE**

PCBMRA89s13F964K

### **VAT CODE**

04230230247



# Mauro Pocobelli

UI designer, passionate about branding and illustration. Freelance at II Sole 24 Ore and open for new collaborations. Currently I am focusing on their design systems to reduce costs and speed up the process, and to have more consistency throughout the products, which are steadily growing in number.

# Work Experience

### **UI DESIGNER**

Il Sole 24 Ore (Milan, 2019 - Present)

I work as a digital designer for the II Sole 24 Ore, the main business newspaper in Italy. I'm in charge of different projects, collaborating with marketing, journalist and IT team. Occasionally I create illustrations for the newspaper.

### Main projects

Norme & Tributi Plus →
Biblioteca24 →

### **LECTURER**

Raffles Milano (Milan, September 2022 - Present)

Teaching digital product design process and direction to the students of the three-years course in Visual design.

# **EDITORIAL DESIGNER**

Mediaprint Editore srl (Verona, August 2017 - June 2019)

I worked as art director of the Pallavolo Supervolley and 365mountainbike Magazine.

### **GRAPHIC DESIGNER**

EazyCity (Cork, Ireland, August 2015 - June 2017)

Member of the Marketing Department composed of an international group, developing concepts, graphics and layouts.

# Education

# UI DESIGN MASTER

Talent Garden Innovation School (Milan, Febraury 2020 - June 2020) Alain Mikli → Welcome →

# **MASTER DEGREE IN COMMUNICATION DESIGN 110/110**

IUAV (Venice, October 2013- April 2015)

<u>Liber Liber →</u>

### **BACHELOR DEGREE IN INDUSTRIAL DESIGN**

Polytechnic of Milan (Como, October 2009 - October 2013)